A Guide to the Richmond (Va.), Bureau of Permits and Inspections, Building permit architectural blueprints and specifications, 1907-1976
Library of Virginia
- Blueprint drawings, 1907-1950, 3167 sets of blueprints
  - Residences-single and multi-family dwellings 1909-1948
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27532, Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Franklin A. Trice, Address: 4605 Coventry Rd., 1945 (Folder 2376)
      Drawn by: John Stafford Efford, Architect, 734 Central National Bank, Richmond, Virginia; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Franklin Trice; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27419, Brick Building to be Used as Indicated 1900-1902-1904 Hull Street, Address: 1900-02-04 Hull St., 1945 (Folder 2385)
      Drawn by: Charles T. Russell, Architect, 412 W. Marshall St.; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: William H. Gregory; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 32308A, [Frame addition], Address: 1434 Claiborne St., 1945 (Folder 2342)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Leary W. Puryear; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27425, A Dwelling for Herman November, Builder & Developer, Address: 4103-05-07 Patterson Ave., 1945 (Folder 2379)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Herman November; Commissioned by: Herman November; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27406, Residence for Mrs. W. D. Miller, Address: 6 Calycanthus Rd., 1945 (Folder 2398)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Franklin A. Trice; Commissioned by: W. D. Miller; Notes: Property is in Windsor Farms
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27488, [Residence] Charles O. Ward, Owner, Address: 4112 Oxford Rd., 1945 (Folder 2447)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Clarence Ward; Notes: Outside of roll notes applicant as "Clarence Ward"
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27452, Residence for Mrs. A. W. Johnson, Address: 26 Rio Vista Ln., 1945 (Folder 2383)
      Drawn by: Foster M. Townsend, Architect, Richmond, Va; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Mrs. A. W. Johnson; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27687, [Residence for Mr. Charles H. Tenser], Address: 5 Clark Rd., 1945 (Folder 2509)
      Drawn by: B. O. Williams; Contractor: B. O. Williams, Building Contractor; Commissioned by: Charles H. Tenser; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27480, Wicker Apartments, Address: 3923-43 Chamberlayne Ave., 1945 (Folder 2386)
      Drawn by: W. H. Pringle, Architect; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Westover Court Corp.; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27233, F. H. A. War Housing, Symbol H-2, Serial No. 051-60021, Address: 2603-05-07-09-11 Park Ave., 1945 (Folder 2361)
      Drawn by: Virginia Apartment Corp. (W. H. Pringle); Contractor: Virginia Apartment Corp. (Muhleman and Kayhoe, Agents); Commissioned by: Virginia Apartment Corp.; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27496, 27497, 27498, [Brick and Frame Residences], Address: 4116-16, 4200-02-04-06-08-10 Hanover Ave.; 4115, 4117 Stuart Ave., 1945 (Folder 2399)
      Drawn by: Otis K. Ashbury, Architect, Richmond, Virginia; Contractor: Franklin A. Trice; Commissioned by: Franklin A. Trice; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27423, Residence for Mr. & Mrs. G. W. Sutton, Sherwood Park, Address: 1607 Brookland Pkwy., 1945 (Folder 2394)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Frye and Shephard, Builders; Commissioned by: G. W. Sutton; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27450, [Brick Residence], Address: 119-29 Roanoke, 1945 (Folder 2395)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Ernest Mayo; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27144, [Brick Residence], Address: 3913 Kensington St., 1945 (Folder 2348)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: George Bayliss; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27161, Chamberlayne Gardens, Address: 4301 Chamberlayne Ave., 1945 (Folder 2357)
      Drawn by: Bernard B. Spigel, Architect, Norfolk, Virgina; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Chamberlayne Gardens; Notes: Part of Federal Housing Administration (Project VA 051-60020)
    - Residence - Permit Number: 31831A, Plans for Second Floor Addition on Rear, Address: 12 W. 19th St., 1945 (Folder 2362)
      Drawn by: Community Home Improvement Co., Inc.; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Sallie Allen; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27543, Dwellings for 29th & 30th between T and V Sts., Address: 1519-29 N. 29th St., 1945 (Folder 2485)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Muhleman and Kayhoe Contractors; Commissioned by: Better Housing, Inc.; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27240, Residence for Mr. M. Imberg, Address: 4415 Monument Ave., 1945 (Folder 2358)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: M. Imberg; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27384, [Residence], Address: 4109 W. Franklin St., 1945 (Folder 2442)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: W. B. Laster; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27195, Site Improvements to and the Construction of Wicker Apartments, Address: 3905-3921 Chamberlayne Ave., 1945 (Folder 2364)
      Drawn by: W. H. Pringle, Architect; Contractor: E. H. Wicker; Commissioned by: Westover Court Corp.; Notes: "A Rental Housing Project, Consisting of Three Apartment Buildings Containing Thirty Dwelling Units;" Federal Housing Authority Project # 051-60022.
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27561, [Residence for Mr. & Mrs. David Carlyle Olgers]], Address: 3119 Sunset Ave., 1945 (Folder 2448)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: J. Edward Seay; Commissioned by: J. Edward Seay; Notes: Specifications note project is for Olgers.
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27194, Brookfield Gardens, Address: Property bounded by Chamberlayne, Bacon, School and Hickory Sts., 1945 (Folder 2354)
      Drawn by: Samuel N. Mayo, Architect, Richmond, Virginia; Holden, McLaughlin & Assoc., Assoc. Architects, NY; Contractor: Allen Saville, Inc., Richmond, Virginia; Commissioned by: Brookfield Gardens; Notes: Part of the Federal Housing Administration (Project 051-60019)
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27220, Residence to be built in Richmond, Va., Franklin A. Trice, Owner & Builder, Address: 29 Clark Rd., 1945 (Folder 2351)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Franklin A. Trice; Commissioned by: Franklin Trice; Notes: Specifications note "-for brick home to be built on Lot #22, Elderslie Place, Richmond, Virginia for Paul E. Cole, Franklin A. Trice, Builder"
    - Residence - Permit Number: 31783A, Proposed Addition to 1800 W. Leigh St., Address: 1800 W. Leigh St., 1945 (Folder 2370)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: General Home Insurance Co.; Commissioned by: Arthur Bangs; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27528, Residence for Mr. and Mrs. M. S. Payne AND Residence for Mr. and Mrs. L.L. Issacs, Address: 1923, 1927 Oakdale Ave., 1945 (Folder 2486)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Frye and Shephard; Commissioned by: Acca Land Co.; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27167, [Residence], Address: 4027-29 Cutshaw St., 1945 (Folder 2371)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Ernest E. Mayo; Commissioned by: Ernest Mayo; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27133, [Residence], Address: 3002-04 Semmes Ave., 1945 (Folder 2349)
      Drawn by: Ruffin & Payne - Building Supplies; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Joseph T. Moore; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27313, Residence for Mr. and Mrs. J.T. Kirkpatrick, Address: 5001 Charmian Rd., 1945 (Folder 2350)
      Drawn by: Courtenay S. Welton, Architect, Richmond; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: J. T. Kirkpatrick; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27462, Residence for Mr. and Mrs. Ernest E. Mayo, Windsor Farms, Address: 4102 Exeter Rd., 1945 (Folder 2372)
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27568, Two Family Brick House, Address: 3406-08-10-12 Cutshaw Ave., 1945 (Folder 2449)
      Drawn by: Eugene H. Brooks, Architect; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Eugene H. Brooks; Notes: 3119 Ellwood Ave. is crossed out in the title block of this set of plans.
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28357, [Residence], Address: 1303, 1307 Chambers St., 1946 (Folder 2713)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: J. M. Wilkinson; Commissioned by: J. M. Wilkinson; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27975, [Residence], Address: 4512-15 Cutshaw Ave., 1946 (Folder 2574)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: E. Ray Richardson; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28013, E. H. Wicker Chatham Place Plan No. 3, Address: 212-14 Laburnum Ave., 1946 (Folder 2571)
      Drawn by: E. H. Wicker; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: E. H. Wicker; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28012, E. H. Wicker, Chatham Place Plan No. 1, Address: 300-02 North Rd.; 216 Laburnum Ave., 1946 (Folder 2572)
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27828, [Residence], Address: 1304-06-08 Carlisle Ave., 1946 (Folder 2710)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: S. R. Clay; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 33467A, Mr. Charles M. Nelson, 6404 Three Chopt Road, Address: 6404 Three Chopt Rd., 1946 (Folder 2695)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Charles Nelson; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28003, Residences for West End Realty Corp., Address: 3322-24-26-28 Meadowbridge Rd., 1946 (Folder 2576)
      Drawn by: Acca Supply Corporation, Prefabricators; Contractor: Muhleman and Kayhoe Contractors; Commissioned by: West End Realty; Notes: "Frame Houses to be in North Highland Park." CD # 155.
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27944, [Residence], Address: 1326 Brookland Parkway, 1946 (Folder 2580)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: H. J. Beckstoffer; Notes: has an attached garage
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28291, Residences for Realty Corporation, Address: 5110-12-14-16 Northampton St., 1946 (Folder 2694)
      Drawn by: Acca Supply Corporation, Prefabricators; Contractor: Emkay Construction Co.; Commissioned by: Realty Corp.; Notes: Specifications for "Twenty-Three Houses in Montebello, Richmond, Virginia. 19 on Garber St. 4 on Northampton St., Job 6200"
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28268, 206 Atlantic Life Bldg, Address: 1001-17 Garber, 1946 (Folder 2625)
      Drawn by: Acca Supply Corporation, Prefabricators; Contractor: Emkay Construction Co.; Commissioned by: Realty Corp.; Notes: same project as permit number 28269. The twenty three houses in Montebello, 19 on Garber St., 4 on Northampton St..
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28408, [Residence], Address: 3600-02-04-10-12 North Ave., 1946 (Folder 2712)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: W. J. Kimbrough; Commissioned by: W. J. Kimbrough; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28404, Residence for West End Realty Corporation, Address: 3410-12-14 Missouri, 1946 (Folder 2706)
      Drawn by: Acca Supply Corporation, Prefabricators; Contractor: West End Realty Corp.; Emkay Construction Co.; Commissioned by: West End Realty; Notes: Specifications for Third Group of Houses in North Highland Park
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27942, Brick Bungalow to be Built on Lot #2, Highland Park, Address: 3203 Detroit, 1946 (Folder 2573)
      Drawn by: Beckstoffer's Sons, 1209 N. 29th St., Richmond, VA; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: C. J. Abernethy; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28356, [Residence], Address: 1301, 1305 Chambers St., 1946 (Folder 2711)
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28374, [Residence], Address: 1113-15-17-23-25-27-29-33-35 Sumter St., 1946 (Folder 2700)
      Drawn by: W. W. La Prade & Bros. Civil Engineers, Richmond, Va; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Samuel Pinchefsky; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27977, [Residence], Address: 3206-14 Condie St., 1946 (Folder 2575)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: F. W. Torrence; Commissioned by: F. W. Torrence; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28337, 3331-33 Stuart Avenue, Address: 3331-33 Stuart Ave., 1946 (Folder 2705)
      Drawn by: Ernest E. Mayo, Builder-Developer; Contractor: Ernest E. Mayo; Commissioned by: Ernest Mayo; Notes: Two-Family Flat Buildings
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28253, [Residence], Address: 509, 519 Granite Ave., 1946 (Folder 2623)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: A. W. Grandis, General Contractor; Commissioned by: Sam Savage; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28327, Graham Brothers, 16 & 1th Streets, Address: 1100-10, 1200-12 E. 17th St., 1946 (Folder 2703)
      Drawn by: E. Tucker Carlton, Architect; Contractor: Graham Brothers, Gordon Avenue, Richmond, Virginia; Commissioned by: OJ & OT Graham; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28365, Duplex Homes for Edward G. Taylor, Address: 4814-18, 4908-22 Chamberlayne Ave., 1946 (Folder 2704)
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28271, [Residence], Address: 3903 Kensington, 1946 (Folder 2621)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: George Whitney; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28269, Residence for Realty Corporation, Address: 1000-18 Garber St., 1946 (Folder 2624)
      Drawn by: Acca Supply Corporation, Prefabricators; Contractor: Emkay Construction Co.; Commissioned by: Realty Corp.; Notes: For 23 houses in Montebello
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28263, [Residence], Address: 3400-02-04-06-07-09-11-13 Hazelhurst Ave.; 3503 Hazelhurst Ave., 1946 (Folder 2622)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Colonial Homes, Inc., 206 Atlantic Life Bldg, Richmond, Virginia; Commissioned by: Colonial Homes; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28395, Residence for Joseph F. Black, Address: 111 Nottingham Rd., 1946 (Folder 2707)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Joseph F. Black, Contractor; Commissioned by: Joseph Black; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28235, Residence, Mr. & Mrs. E. B. Sydnor, Jr., Address: 6000 St. Andrews Lane, 1946 (Folder 2604)
      Drawn by: Marcellus E. Wright, Architect, American Nat'l Bank Bldg., Richmond, VA; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: E. B. Sydnor Jr.; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28304, [Residence], Address: 4208 W. Franklin St., 1946 (Folder 2620)
      Drawn by: B. O. Williams; Contractor: B. O. Williams, Building Contractor; Commissioned by: W. N. Katz; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28252, Duplex Frame Residence, Address: 602-04-06 E. Brookland Blvd., 1946 (Folder 2602)
      Drawn by: E. Tucker Carlton, Architect; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Avery Housing; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28256, Residence for West End Realty Corp., Address: 3501-03-05 Meadowbridge Rd., 1946 (Folder 2603)
      Drawn by: Acca Supply Corporation, Prefabricators; Contractor: West End Realty Corp.; Emkay Construction Co.; Commissioned by: West End Realty; Notes: "Specifications for Third Group of Frame Houses in North Highland Park, Richmond, VA, Job 6500"
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28240, [Residence], Address: 3708-10-12-14 W. Cary St., 1946 (Folder 2608)
      Drawn by: Ernest E. Mayo, Builder-Developer; Contractor: Ernest E. Mayo; Commissioned by: Ernest Mayo; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28335, [Residence], Address: 3206 Franklin, 1946 (Folder 2607)
      Drawn by: Ernest E. Mayo, Builder-Developer; Contractor: Ernest E. Mayo; Commissioned by: Ernest Mayo; Notes: Two-Family Flat Building Brick Residence
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28443, [Residence], Address: 516, 518, 536 Granite Ave., 1946 (Folder 2637)
      Drawn by: R. C. Meagher; Contractor: Walker Construction Co.; Commissioned by: Walker Construction; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28267, Third Group of Frame Houses in North Highland Park, Address: 3409-11-13 Missouri Ave., 1946 (Folder 2606)
      Drawn by: Acca Supply Corporation, Prefabricators; Contractor: Emkay Construction Co.; Commissioned by: West End Realty; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28018, [Residence], Address: 5010 Caledonia Rd., 1946 (Folder 2586)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: J. Leonard Moore; Commissioned by: Charles Freeman; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28260, Third Group of Frame Houses in North Highland Park, Address: 3403-19 Meadowbridge Rd., 1946 (Folder 2605)
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28418, [Residence], Address: 801-13, 901-03 W. 49th St.; 4807 Bassett Ave., 1946 (Folder 2644)
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28423, Duplex Frame Residence, Address: 506-08 E. Brookland Park Blvd., 1946 (Folder 2640)
      Drawn by: E. Tucker Carlton, Architect; Contractor: Roslyn Homes Inc.; Commissioned by: Roslyn Homes; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28438, [Residence], Address: 1300-02-10 Carlisle Ave., 1946 (Folder 2643)
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28670, [Residence], Address: 5106 Caledonia Rd., 1946 (Folder 2812)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: J. M. Wilkinson; Commissioned by: J. M. Wilkinson; Notes: Two-story, three-bedroom, brick colonial revival house with slate roof.
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28417, Drawings of Residence for Col. And Mrs. Oliver F. Marston, Address: 104 Nottingham Rd., 1946 (Folder 2642)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Col. O. F. Marson; Notes: in Windsor Farms
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27948, 27949, 27958, 27960, Four Room Ready Cut, Address: 1200-11 Orleans, 1205-11 Nelwood Dr., 1946 (Folder 2570)
      Drawn by: Forehand - Taylor, Lynchburg, Virginia; Contractor: Chas. W. Smith and W. C. Chewning, Builders and Owners; Commissioned by: Chewning & Smith; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28246, [Residence], Address: N/A, 1946 (Folder 2615)
      Drawn by: Stratford Johnson Quality Homes; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: University of Richmond; Notes: For six houses. Plans include detail for construction of houses.
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28004, Residence for Better Housing Inc., Address: 1600-24 N. 31st St., 1946 (Folder 2582)
      Drawn by: Acca Supply Corporation, Prefabricators; Contractor: Emkay Construction Co.; Commissioned by: Better Housing Inc.; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27970, Better Homes and Gardens Home Plan, Address: 5409 Toddsbury Rd., 1946 (Folder 2584)
      Drawn by: Theodore Whitehead Davis, Architect, Better Homes and Gardens; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Archer P. Stone; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28371, 28372, [Residence], Address: 2706-22 Haden; 3309-11, 3401-09 Ritter, 1946 (Folder 2714)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Enal Inc.; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28360, [Residence], Address: 2705-21 Lamberts Ave., 1946 (Folder 2715)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Enal, Inc.; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28376, [Residence], Address: 3202-08 Bute Lane, 1946 (Folder 2716)
      Drawn by: J. Edward Seay, Builder; Contractor: J. Edward Seay; Commissioned by: J. Edward Seay; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28385, [Residence], Address: 218-24 Larne Ave.; 4400 McRae, 1946 (Folder 2718)
      Drawn by: George W. Bradley, General Contractor; Contractor: George W. Bradley; Commissioned by: George W. Bradley; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28312, [Residence], Address: 509, 607-09, 610-12 Jasper; 505-13, 512, 706, 710-12, 803-11 Walker; 506-08, 806-08, 815-17, 902 Lincoln; 508-10, 805, 810, 813-15, 814, 819-21 Chtwd, 1946 (Folder 2599)
      Drawn by: E. Tucker Carlton, Architect; American Houses, New York; Contractor: Avery Housing Corp, Richmond, Va; Commissioned by: Washington Park Land Corp.; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28248, 28249, 28250, 28251, 28252, Frame and Brick Veneer Residences for Rose and Lafoon, Inc., Address: 517-19-21 Montvale; 307-09-11 Napoleon; 3101-17 Napoleon; 3005 Alvis; 601-11 Craigie; 600-10 Craigie; 602-04-06 E. Brookland Blvd., 1946 (Folder 2618)
      Drawn by: E. Tucker Carlton, Architect; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Avery Housing; Notes: Specifications say "for Roslyn Homes Inc."
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27950, 27951, Residence for Realty Corporation, Address: 4903-05 Patterson Ave.; 5003-05 Patterson Ave., 1946 (Folder 2588)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Emkay Construction Co.; Commissioned by: West End Realty Co.; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28295, 5300 Block Willow Lawn, "Glenburnie", Address: 5302-10 Willow Lawn, 1946 (Folder 2611)
      Drawn by: Andrew L. Kidwell, Designer & Builder; Contractor: Andrew L. Kidwell, Designer and Builder; Commissioned by: Matt P. Will; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28255, [Residence], Address: 1201-03-05 Hampton, 1946 (Folder 2601)
      Drawn by: S. E. Turner J. N. Ladd Home Designers; Contractor: E. Carlton, Builder; Commissioned by: S. M. Wilton; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28296, Two Family Brick House, Address: 3401-03-05 Cutshaw Ave., 1946 (Folder 2610)
      Drawn by: Eugene H. Brooks, Architect; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Eugene H. Brooks; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27793, Frame Bungalow for B. C. Cobb, Summer Hill Plaza, Address: 3018-20-22-24 Krouse St., 1946 (Folder 2609)
      Drawn by: E. Tucker Carlton, Architect; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: B. C. Cobb; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27943, Better Homes and Gardens Home Plan, Address: 5008 Evelyn Byrd Rd., 1946 (Folder 2585)
      Drawn by: Kenneth W. Dalzell, Better Homes and Gardens; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: J. T. Wood, Jr.; Notes: Also includes plans for some of the details. CD # 155.
    - Residence - Permit Number: 27945, [Residence], Address: 1912-16-20-24-26-28 Westwood, 1946 (Folder 2581)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Acca Land Co.; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28391, [Residence], Address: 1601-15, 1701-09 Meadowbridge Rd., 1946 (Folder 2709)
      Drawn by: S. E. Turner J. N. Ladd Home Designers; Contractor: E. Carlton Wilton, Builder; Commissioned by: E. Carlton Wilton; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28005, Residences for Better Housing Inc., Address: 1601-19 N. 30th St., 1946 (Folder 2578)
      Drawn by: Acca Supply Corporation, Prefabricators; Contractor: Emkay Construction Co.; Commissioned by: Better Housing Inc.; Notes: "Twenty three frame houses to be erected on thirtieth and thirty-first Street between 'V' and Nine Mile Road."
    - Residence - Permit Number: 29881, Houses for Ed C. Wilton, Address: 3601-03 Floyd Ave., 1946 (Folder 2535)
      Drawn by: Carl M. Lindner; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: E. C. Wilton; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28168, Residence for Mr. W E. Seaton, Jr., Address: 4304 Dover Rd., 1946 (Folder 2474)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: Franklin A. Trice; Commissioned by: Wm. Seaton; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28118, Residence, Mr. & Mrs. Charles Roe, Address: 5900 River Rd., 1946 (Folder 2473)
      Drawn by: Marcellus Wright & Son, Architects, Richmond, Virginia; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Charles Rose; Notes: Plot plan showing Country Club of Virginia, Moseley Property, etc.
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28179, A Residence for George Grandis, Address: 4619-21 Fitzhugh Ave., 1946 (Folder 2472)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: George Grandis; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28102, [Residence], Address: 1126-40 Sumpter St., 1946 (Folder 2471)
      Drawn by: Unsigned; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Samuel Pinchetsky; Notes: small note saying "specifications filed with 28374- Nov. 8, 1946"
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28225, Four Room Ready-Cut 28' x 24', Address: 1102-04-06 Goddin Rd., 1946 (Folder 2469)
      Drawn by: Forehand - Taylor, Lynchburg, Virginia; Contractor: N/A; Commissioned by: Smith & Chewning; Notes:
    - Residence - Permit Number: 28033, [Residence], Address: 4400 W. Franklin St., 1946 (Folder 2514)
      Drawn by: Ruffin & Payne - Building Supplies; Contractor: B. B. Orange; Commissioned by: Jas B. Higgins; Notes: